we've got another kettlebell video for
you guys and if you don't already know
kettlebell training has a whole lot of
benefits because not only are you going
to get stronger by swinging one of these
funky shaped pieces of iron around which
also going to improve your cardio at the
exact same time now kettlebell Kings has
solidified their name with their high
quality kettlebells and they've got a
few different options for you to choose
from but today we're going to be
breaking down their powder coated option
there's a lot going on here so let's go
ahead and get right to it
[Music]
thank you what's up everybody it's Jake
back in the barbing garage gym and for
today's video I've got the powder coat
kettlebell from kettlebell Kings if you
don't know how this works in this video
today I'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about this piece of
equipment we're going to talk about the
price we're going to talk about some
pros and cons but most importantly going
to talk about who should or maybe should
not scoop one of these bad boys up now
before I start doing you know all of
that and giving you my whole Spiel I got
to let you know we reviewed a ton of
kettlebells on barbin.com so if you want
to browse our best list all you got to
do is search bar Bend best kettlebells
our list is going to pull right up for
you and you can find out for yourself
which one cracks that number one spot
[Music]
so let's talk about some of the things I
like about this powder coat kettlebell
first of all we've got to talk about
texture texture matters with all
equipment whether that be dumbbells or
barbell and in this case you know
obviously a kettlebell and I gotta say
that's something that this bad boy just
really has got going on in my opinion
gives you a really nice grip whenever
you're working out doesn't feel too
rough on your skin when you're working
out and I don't have any chalk on me
right now but we have you know tested
chalk with this kettlebell and it you
know still worked well and it gave us a
really good grip which is a really nice
thing this is one single piece of cast
iron so there's no welding or plugs or
anything right here it's really nice for
durability you don't have to worry about
the Bell on the handle ever coming loose
also has a lifetime warranty which is a
really nice touch right there too but
kettlebell Kings uses a gravity casting
process with their kettlebells and if
you don't know what that is I'm just
going to summarize really quick
basically it's just going to give you
the most accurate reading with your
weight which is a really nice thing you
don't want to be you know swinging
around a kettlebell it's either too
heavy or you know not heavy enough you
know of what is advertised on the bill
which is nice another thing I really
liked about kettlebell Kings is that
they actually polish their kettlebells
from any imperfections so whenever you
take a kettlebell out of the mold
there's rough edges and a lot of times
you know companies will just kind of
fill that in with putty or you know
paint over it whatever it is it looks
you know fine on the surface level but
over time that's kind of going to break
down and you know kettlebell Kings
doesn't do that so that's just a really
nice thing is you're going to get you
know a really high quality product
whenever you make your purchase there's
also 21 different buying options which I
think is you know nothing short of
Awesome from four kilograms all the way
up to 92 kilograms that's nine pounds to
around 203 pounds which is really nice
you know every athlete essentially is
going to be able to find the Kettlebell
that you know suits their needs there's
also free shipping free shipping is
awesome if you've never had to ship a
kettlebell before you know how big of a
pain that is and how expensive that is
that's obviously just a really nice
thing and the lastly right here I really
like this machine finished flat base you
know a lot of times with kettlebells
it's rough down here and it can kind of
lead to them a wobble you know a little
bit whenever you go to set them down on
the ground and that's just not going to
happen here and I think we all can get
behind that
[Music]
all right now you know typically in
these videos I sit here and list off a
couple you know potential cons you may
have with you know any product but
honestly y'all with this kettlebell
right here only thing in my opinion is
just the money you know this is an
expensive kettlebell I'm gonna you know
detail pricing in just a minute but
their kettlebells are more expensive all
across the board than pretty much all
the competitions so definitely just keep
that in mind
[Music]
now let's talk about some money with
these powder coat kettlebells and before
I start doing all that workout equipment
gym equipment it's always going to
fluctuate with price so you know
companies often you know have quick
sales so bump up the price out of
nowhere so definitely just keep that in
mind these are the prices as of right
now okay and we're gonna be referring to
these in pounds so cheapest option is
that nine pound kettlebell it's gonna
run you around 75 bucks or so this 48
pound bill is around 120 and you know if
you're the most jacked person on the
face of the planet that 203 pound belt
it's gonna run you around 425 dollars
now these are expensive there's you know
no getting around that these are
expensive kettlebells and they're more
expensive than pretty much every other
option on the market but that's also
because shipping is technically included
with that price tag it's listed as free
but it's pretty much included so if you
compare you know these kettlebells to
Rogues all across the board you know
Rogues are cheaper you know on paper but
you have to pay for shipping with Rogue
and then of course taxes which you still
have taxes with this maybe about 15
bucks or so anyways it's going to wind
up you know balancing out in the long
run which Rogue actually might be a
little bit more expensive by you know a
few bucks or so just because of having
to you know pay for that shipping so
just definitely keep that in mind
also you know another thing here yes
this is a very nice kettlebell but
you're paying 120 bucks for one single
kettlebell
so you know if you can't really stomach
the fact of doing that you might be
better off going after an adjustable
kettlebell system because you know a lot
of those are going to be cheaper than
this or right around the same price as
this right here and you get you know
obviously more options for you to work
with so definitely keep that in mind at
the end of the day though you know if
you're just looking for you know good
old-fashioned classic cast iron
kettlebell this is a really solid option
for you to you know choose from
it's going to last you a really long
time plus you have that lifetime
warranty which is just really tough to
beat and also the quality like I said
just top tier in my opinion
[Applause]
[Music]
now kettlebells don't have a whole lot
of features but let's talk about some of
the ones that are you know evident with
this kettlebell and just the overall
build alright so since these are not
competition kettlebells the overall size
is going to be determined by you know
which weight you decide to purchase okay
now there's a full chart on the
Kettlebell Kings website that you know
breaks down all the dimensions for all
the kettlebells so I'm not going to do
all that definitely check it out though
it's really helpful all right so the
handle right here is 39 millimeters
which is pretty thick it's going to give
you a really nice grip as you're working
out which is obviously a really good
thing and it stands about six and a half
inches tall
now once again this is one single piece
of cast iron so there's no welding right
here you know with the handle and the
bell it's not going to come loose over
time but also once again kettlebell
Kings uses a gravity casting process
with their kettlebells and I mentioned
you know that's how you get that
pinpoint accuracy you know with your
weight but if you don't know what that
means basically what they're doing is
pouring into the mold for these
kettlebells and just allowing gravity
you know to take care of the rest of the
work so it's not getting pressurized or
anything like that so it's just overall
you know a better process to make your
kettlebell now
it's a nice machine finished flat base
right here there's no roughness at all
right here there's no grooves anything
so there's not going to be anything
interfering you know with the Bell on
the floor to make it not sit flat which
is a good thing you don't want it to
just you know kind of topple over as you
go to set it down maybe doing your you
know kettlebell stop swings anything
like that it's not going to fall on you
which is obviously a really really nice
thing right there now you do have your
color-coded handles right here this is
the case for all the kettlebells up to I
think 106 pounds anything after that
anything 123 and on it's not going to
have a color-coded handle which is nice
you know you just memorize what color
represents what weight you just grab it
and you're good to go and then lastly
you know can't forget about the powder
coat finish you use the powder coated
kettlebells it feels great in my hands
honestly gives me really good grip on
its own if you want to use chalk it's
going to work well with chalk you know
if that's your preference and you know
anytime you go and put it in that rack
position it really just doesn't hurt
doesn't irritate your skin which is a
very nice thing I think we all can
appreciate that
all right so I just want to you know
reiterate on a few things for you guys
and just kind of show them you know
showcase everything up close so once
again we have the 48 pound kettlebell
that's what this green is signifying
right here it's gonna be really helpful
you know especially if you purchase
multiple kettlebells you know what color
you know represents what weight you just
grab it and get straight to your workout
this handle is 39 millimeters in
diameter all the way around right here
gives you a really solid grip fills your
palm really nicely and you know once
again this is going to work well with
chalk so if that's kind of you know your
preference with kettlebell training
that's going to be really nice thing for
you and then I just want to show you up
close you know as you can see there is
no welding right here with these handles
and the actual Bell that's what you're
looking for with the Kettlebell you know
you don't want that weld
it's gonna you know it's probably gonna
take a long time for it to wear down but
still it's something you don't have to
worry about whatsoever with this
kettlebell
on the front right here you know you got
your kettlebell logo the king is just
kind of cool in my opinion just looks
pretty sweet it's indented right here so
it's not gonna you know rub your arm the
wrong way or anything like that and then
on the back you know it's labeled in
both kilograms and pounds which is just
nice for you know obvious reasons and
then really my one of my favorite things
right here is this machine finished flat
base so it's wide it's going to give you
that nice wide base so it's not gonna
you know topple over or anything but
also this is beautiful honestly this is
pretty perfect there's no ridges there's
no lines there's no bumps there's
nothing right here it's about as perfect
as it gets and then really lastly y'all
just texture you know already talked
about how it works well with chalk but
you know you put this bad boy in that
racked position right here and it
doesn't like irritate your skin doesn't
irritate my skin at all and it's
definitely something you want to avoid
whenever you're going to purchase a
kettlebell so you know through and
through all you know everything about it
it's a really really nice kettlebell in
my opinion
[Music]
all right now let's talk about who
should or maybe should not purchase one
of these powder coat kettlebells from
kettlebell Kings and I think we should
talk about who should first all right so
if quality is your driving factor with
equipment which it probably should be
this is honestly about as good as it
gets you know they do have that they do
use that gravity casting process you
know this is one single piece of cast
iron
this is you know top-notch in my opinion
and then also if you're looking for a
wide range of weight options once again
there's 21 different weights you can
choose from between nine pounds 203
pounds so you're gonna be able to find a
kettlebell that meets your needs and
then when it comes to those who might
not want to purchase this kettlebell
really y'all I mean it okay so first if
you're into kettlebell Sport and you
want all your kettlebells to be the
uniform size well this is not a
competition kettlebell I highly suggest
going to get a competition kettlebell
but kettlebell Kings actually has some
so you might want to go check those out
and then really it's just the price you
know these are pretty pricey to say the
least so you know if you can't stomach
spending you know a whole bunch of money
on a full set of kettlebells might want
to go and get an adjustable kettlebell
system it's going to cost you about the
same amount of money as this one single
kettlebell
all right well that's all I got for
y'all today on the powder coat
kettlebells from kettlebell Kings I know
I've been talking about how you know
these are pretty pricey but you're
definitely getting what you're paying
for so you know once again one single
piece of cast iron they definitely use
that gravity casting process plus you
get that lifetime warranty which is you
know a really nice touch but it feels
really good in my hands you know there's
a lot of different weight options for
you to choose from there's a lot going
on right here that you know I think
everybody can get behind thanks for
watching y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and that I was able to
tell you everything you need to know
about these kettlebells as always stay
on the lookout for my next video but for
now I want you to head over to
barvin.com so we have a full written
article just waiting for you to read it
it's going to pop up in this corner
right here but I still want you to
search bar Bend kettlebell Kings powder
coated kettlebell review it's going to
pull right up for you and you can go
over every single thing we talked about
here today I'll catch y'all next time
thank you
foreign